In Python, you can create lists really quickly and
在 Python 中 你可以使用一个非常酷的工具
concisely with a cool tool called List Comprehensions.
快速简洁地创建列表 该工具叫做列表推导式
In the cities example from earlier,
在之前的 cities 示例中
we created a list of capitalized cities from the cities list in a for loop.
我们用 for 循环通过 cities 列表创建了一个首字母大写的城市列表
With a list comprehension,
借助列表推导式
we can get the same result like this.
我们可以像这样获得相同的结果
List comprehensions allow us to create a list using a for loop in one step.
借助列表推导式 我们可以使用 for 循环用一步就创建一个列表
You create a list comprehension with brackets including
列表推导式的创建方式是使用方括号
an expression to evaluate for each element in an iterable.
括号内是一个表达式 用于评估可迭代对象中的每个元素
This line called city.title for
这行对 cities 中的每个元素调用 city.title()
each element in cities to create each element in the new list.
以便在新列表中创建每个元素
Notice this part looks just like the first line of a for loop without a colon,
注意 这部分看起来和 for 循环的第一行很像 只是没有冒号
and the action you want to take on each element is taking on the element here,
你想对每个元素执行的操作在这里执行
and append it to this new list.
并将执行后的元素附加到这个新列表中
In the list comprehension,
在列表推导式中
we don't need to create a new list
我们不需要提前新建一个列表
beforehand and append to it like we would in a for loop.
并向其附加元素 就像在 for 循环中那样
List comprehensions are not found in other languages,
列表推导式并不适用于其他语言
but are very common in Python.
但是在 Python 中很常见
Here's another example that creates a list of squares from 0 to 64.
这是另一个创建平方和（从 0 到 64）列表的示例
This line called X to the power of two for every element
这行针对 range(9) 中的每个元素调用 x 的 2 次幂
in range nine to create each element in the new list, squares.
以便为新列表 squares 创建每个元素
We can write this as a list comprehension like this.
我们可以将这段代码写成列表推导式 像这样
Again, we are just looping through each element in
重申一下 我们只是遍历该可迭代对象中的每个元素
this iterable and evaluating this expression to get each new element in our list.
并评估此表达式以获取列表中的每个新元素
You can also add conditionals to list comprehensions.
还可以向列表推导式中添加条件语句
After the iterable, you can use the If keyword to check a condition in each iteration.
你可以在可迭代对象之后使用关键字 if 检查每次迭代时是否满足某个条件
In this example, X to the power of two is only evaluated if X is even.
在此示例中 仅在 X 为偶数时才计算 X 的 2 次幂
This gives us a list only including squares of even numbers.
这样就获得只包含偶数平方的列表
If you want to add an Else,
如果像这样添加 else 语句
you will get a syntax error doing this.
就会遇到语法错误
If you'd like to add Else,
如果你要添加 else 语句
you have to move the conditionals to the beginning of
则需要将条件语句移到列表推导式的开头
the list comprehension right after the expression like this.
并放在该表达式之后 就像这样
Details on why this is the case are in the notes below.
要了解为何要这样添加 else 语句 请参阅下方的注释